export const midtermque =
[
    {
      id: 58,
      question: 'The climax near Tindni village is being controlled by disturbance by cattle. This is an example of',
      options: [
        'climatic climax',
        'edaphic climax',
        'disclimax',
        'catastrophic climax'
      ],
      answer: 'disclimax'
    },
    {
      id: 49,
      question: 'Which of these is true?',
      options: [
        'Physiological longevity > Ecological longevity',
        'Physiological longevity = Ecological longevity',
        'Physiological longevity < Ecological longevity',
        'a or b'
      ],
      answer: 'a or b'
    },
    {
      id: 52,
      question: 'A species found most frequently in a particular community, but also present occasionally in others is called',
      options: [
        'accidental species',
        'indifferent species',
        'selective species',
        'exclusive species'
      ],
      answer: 'selective species'
    },
    {
      id: 34,
      question: 'At the compensation point,',
      options: [
        'photosynthesis = respiration',
        'photosynthesis < respiration',
        'photosynthesis > respiration',
        'photosynthesis = 0'
      ],
      answer: 'photosynthesis = respiration'
    },
    {
      id: 32,
      question: 'Trees → Birds → Parasites → Hyperparasites represents',
      options: [
        'upright pyramid of numbers',
        'inverted pyramid of numbers',
        'spindle pyramid of numbers',
        'dumb-bell pyramid of numbers'
      ],
      answer: 'inverted pyramid of numbers'
    },
    {
      id: 55,
      question: 'Lithosere is an example of',
      options: [ 'hydrosere', 'xerosere', 'psammosere', 'halosere' ],
      answer: 'xerosere'
    },
    {
      id: 33,
      question: 'Net primary productivity is given by',
      options: [ 'APAR × LUE', 'APAR + LUE', 'APAR - LUE', 'APAR / LUE' ],
      answer: 'APAR × LUE'
    },
    {
      id: 50,
      question: '___ is how close the measured values are to the correct value.',
      options: [ 'Accuracy', 'Precision', 'Bias', 'Variance' ],
      answer: 'Accuracy'
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question: 'In the Greek word root of Ecology, Oikos refers to',
      options: [ 'household', 'preservation', 'environment', 'study' ],
      answer: 'household'
    },
    {
      id: 31,
      question: "If we all became vegetarians, we'll be able to support our large populations. This can be explained through",
      options: [ '10% rule', '1% rule', 'trophic cascade', 'biodiversity' ],
      answer: '10% rule'
    },
    {
      id: 44,
      question: 'Which of these is not a measure of absolute population density?',
      options: [
        'total count',
        'pelt count',
        'capture-recapture method',
        'removal method'
      ],
      answer: 'pelt count'
    },
    {
      id: 48,
      question: 'Cover board surveys are typically used for sampling',
      options: [ 'herpetofauna', 'fishes', 'large mammals', 'carnivores' ],
      answer: 'herpetofauna'
    },
    {
      id: 26,
      question: 'Interaction between exotic shrubs and trees through seed predators is an example of',
      options: [
        'infraspecific competition',
        'apparent competition',
        'disguised competition',
        'harmonious competition'
      ],
      answer: 'apparent competition'
    },
    {
      id: 35,
      question: 'Consider the food chain: Grass → Grasshopper → Frog → Snake → Hawk. As we move up the food chain,',
      options: [
        'available energy decreases',
        'available energy increases',
        'available energy remains same',
        'available energy is zero everywhere'
      ],
      answer: 'available energy decreases'
    },
    {
      id: 53,
      question: 'When compared to generalist species, specialist species have',
      options: [
        'narrower niches',
        'broader niches',
        'same-size niches',
        'none of these'
      ],
      answer: 'narrower niches'
    },
    {
      id: 43,
      question: '___ employs a simple rule of selecting every kth unit starting with a number chosen at random from 1 to k as the random start.',
      options: [
        'Simple random sampling',
        'Systematic sampling',
        'Stratified sampling',
        'Multistage sampling'
      ],
      answer: 'Systematic sampling'
    },
    {
      id: 51,
      question: 'Importance value can be written as',
      options: [
        'Relative density + Relative frequency X Relative dominance',
        'Relative density X Relative frequency + Relative dominance',
        'Relative density + Relative frequency + Relative dominance',
        'Relative density X Relative frequency X Relative dominance'
      ],
      answer: 'Relative density + Relative frequency + Relative dominance'
    },
    {
      id: 40,
      question: 'Consider the food chain: Grass → Grasshopper → Frog → Snake → Hawk. In this food chain,',
      options: [
        'frog is producer',
        'frog is consumer and carnivore',
        'frog is consumer and herbivore',
        'frog is decomposer'
      ],
      answer: 'frog is consumer and carnivore'
    },
    {
      id: 20,
      question: 'For more biodiversity, the level of disturbance should be',
      options: [ 'less', 'intermediate', 'more', 'none of these' ],
      answer: 'intermediate'
    },
    {
      id: 1,
      question: 'Which of these is not a step in natural selection?',
      options: [
        'variation',
        'underpopulation',
        'struggle for existence',
        'survival of the fittest'
      ],
      answer: 'underpopulation'
    },
    {
      id: 29,
      question: 'An inventory of behaviours exhibited by an animal is called',
      options: [ 'ecogram', 'ethogram', 'behaviourogram', 'animalogram' ],
      answer: 'ethogram'
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: '“Enquiry into plants” is a book written by',
      options: [ 'Theophrastus', 'Linnaeus', 'Malthus', 'Humboldt' ],
      answer: 'Theophrastus'
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question: 'The hierarchical system was given by',
      options: [ 'Simon', 'Watson', 'Hutchinson', 'Humboldt' ],
      answer: 'Simon'
    },
    {
      id: 16,
      question: 'The diversity within an ecosystem is known as',
      options: [
        'alpha (α) biodiversity',
        'beta (β) biodiversity',
        'gamma (γ) biodiversity',
        'delta (δ) biodiversity'
      ],
      answer: 'alpha (α) biodiversity'
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question: 'The mitochondrion is a/an:',
      options: [ 'Sub-cellular organelle', 'Cell', 'Tissue', 'Organ' ],
      answer: 'Sub-cellular organelle'
    },
    {
      id: 42,
      question: 'Pan traps are used for sampling',
      options: [
        'bees',
        'butterflies',
        'non-pollinator insects',
        'pollinator insects'
      ],
      answer: 'pollinator insects'
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: 'Ecology is the scientific study of interactions among organisms and their ___.',
      options: [ 'habitat', 'niche', 'environment', 'population' ],
      answer: 'environment'
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: 'Which of these is not a kind of selection',
      options: [ 'directional', 'stochastic', 'disruptive', 'stabilising' ],
      answer: 'stochastic'
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: 'Ecology is the scientific study of ___ that determine the distribution and abundance of organisms.',
      options: [ 'statics', 'interactions', 'dynamics', 'habitat' ],
      answer: 'interactions'
    },
    {
      id: 45,
      question: 'The logistic growth equation, when plotted, appears',
      options: [ 'I shaped', 'J shaped', 'S shaped', 'O shaped' ],
      answer: 'S shaped'
    },
    {
      id: 18,
      question: 'The emergent principle can be stated as',
      options: [
        'Whole = sum of parts',
        'Whole < sum of parts',
        'Whole > sum of parts',
        'None of these'
      ],
      answer: 'Whole > sum of parts'
    },
    {
      id: 21,
      question: 'Egrets with buffaloes are an example of',
      options: [ 'colony', 'commensalism', 'protocooperation', 'allelopathy' ],
      answer: 'commensalism'
    },
    {
      id: 37,
      question: 'Tree → Frugivorous birds → Hawk represents',
      options: [
        'upright pyramid of numbers',
        'inverted pyramid of numbers',
        'spindle pyramid of numbers',
        'dumb-bell pyramid of numbers'
      ],
      answer: 'spindle pyramid of numbers'
    },
    {
      id: 57,
      question: 'Importance value varies from',
      options: [ '0 to 10', '0 to 50', '0 to 100', '0 to 300' ],
      answer: '0 to 300'
    },
    {
      id: 46,
      question: 'A sampling procedure such that each possible combination of sampling units out of the population has the same chance of being selected is referred to as',
      options: [
        'Simple random sampling',
        'Systematic sampling',
        'Stratified sampling',
        'Multistage sampling'
      ],
      answer: 'Simple random sampling'
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question: 'Hierarchy emerges almost inevitably through a variety of evolutionary processes. Why?',
      options: [ 'perfect', 'imperfect', 'stable', 'unstable' ],
      answer: 'stable'
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question: "The definition of 'species' involves",
      options: [ 'cells', 'species', 'ecosystems', 'biomes' ],
      answer: 'species'
    },
    {
      id: 39,
      question: 'Glacial lakes are typical examples of',
      options: [
        'eutrophic lakes',
        'hypereutrophic lakes',
        'oligotrophic lakes',
        'mesotrophic lakes'
      ],
      answer: 'oligotrophic lakes'
    },
    {
      id: 56,
      question: 'Which of these is correct?',
      options: [
        'Fundamental niche > Realised niche',
        'Fundamental niche = Realised niche',
        'Fundamental niche < Realised niche',
        'a or b'
      ],
      answer: 'a or b'
    },
    {
      id: 60,
      question: 'Which of these depicts correctly the lithosere primary succession?',
      options: [
        'Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax',
        'Rock → Foliose lichen → Crustose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax',
        'Moss → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Rock → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax',
        'Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Shrub → Herbaceous stage → Moss → Woodland → Climax'
      ],
      answer: 'Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax'
    },
    {
      id: 22,
      question: "Observing a monkey take a tick out of another monkey's head and eat it is an example of",
      options: [ 'tick hunting', 'auto grooming', 'allo grooming', 'foraging' ],
      answer: 'allo grooming'
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question: 'In the Greek word root of Ecology, logos refers to',
      options: [ 'household', 'preservation', 'environment', 'study' ],
      answer: 'study'
    },
    {
      id: 30,
      question: "Hamilton's rule can be stated as",
      options: [ 'rB < C', 'rB > C', 'rB = C', 'rB + C = 0' ],
      answer: 'rB > C'
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question: 'Which of these is not a characteristic of fitness?',
      options: [
        'Fitness is environment-specific.',
        'Fitness is species-specific.',
        'Fitness works on traits such as size and speed.',
        'Fitness should be measured across several generations.'
      ],
      answer: 'Fitness works on traits such as size and speed.'
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: 'Which of these is not a characteristic of fitness?',
      options: [
        'Fitness is environment-specific.',
        'Fitness is species-specific.',
        'Higher reproductive rate means higher fitness.',
        'Fitness should be measured across several generations.'
      ],
      answer: 'Higher reproductive rate means higher fitness.'
    },
    {
      id: 23,
      question: 'Birds on giraffe are an example of',
      options: [ 'colony', 'commensalism', 'protocooperation', 'allelopathy' ],
      answer: 'protocooperation'
    },
    {
      id: 17,
      question: 'The diversity among different geographies is known as',
      options: [
        'alpha (α) biodiversity',
        'beta (β) biodiversity',
        'gamma (γ) biodiversity',
        'delta (δ) biodiversity'
      ],
      answer: 'gamma (γ) biodiversity'
    },
    {
      id: 47,
      question: 'The minimum replacement level fertility for a population to grow should be greater than',
      options: [ '1', '2', '3', '4' ],
      answer: '2'
    },
    {
      id: 38,
      question: 'Consider the food chain: Grass → Grasshopper → Frog → Snake → Hawk. In this food chain,',
      options: [
        'hawk is producer',
        'hawk is consumer and carnivore',
        'hawk is consumer and herbivore',
        'hawk is decomposer'
      ],
      answer: 'hawk is consumer and carnivore'
    },
    {
      id: 54,
      question: 'A climax caused by wildfires is an example of',
      options: [
        'climatic climax',
        'edaphic climax',
        'disclimax',
        'catastrophic climax'
      ],
      answer: 'catastrophic climax'
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question: 'Who amongst these is considered the father of Biogeography?',
      options: [ 'Theophrastus', 'Linnaeus', 'Malthus', 'Humboldt' ],
      answer: 'Humboldt'
    },
    {
      id: 41,
      question: 'The juvenile mortality rate is the annual number of deaths of juveniles per',
      options: [
        '100 births',
        '1000 births',
        '100 live births',
        '1000 live births'
      ],
      answer: '1000 live births'
    },
    {
      id: 28,
      question: 'The scientific study of animal behaviour is called',
      options: [ 'behaviourism', 'ecology', 'ethology', 'prey-predator dynamics' ],
      answer: 'ethology'
    },
    {
      id: 27,
      question: 'Trampling of grass due to animal movement is an example of',
      options: [ 'mutualism', 'amensalism', 'commensalism', 'protocooperation' ],
      answer: 'amensalism'
    },
    {
      id: 25,
      question: "Observing a bird take a tick out of another bird's head and eat it is an example of",
      options: [ 'tick hunting', 'auto grooming', 'allo grooming', 'foraging' ],
      answer: 'allo grooming'
    },
    {
      id: 19,
      question: 'The laboratory approach to Ecology uses',
      options: [ 'equations', 'models', 'observations', 'experiments' ],
      answer: 'experiments'
    },
    {
      id: 24,
      question: 'Harmonious interactions occur where',
      options: [
        'at least one participant is benefited',
        'at least one participant is unharmed',
        'both participants are benefitted',
        'both participants are unharmed'
      ],
      answer: 'both participants are unharmed'
    },
    {
      id: 59,
      question: 'Which of these is not a characteristic of pioneer species',
      options: [
        'ability to grow on bare rocks',
        'ability to tolerate extreme temperatures',
        'large size',
        'short life span'
      ],
      answer: 'large size'
    },
    {
      id: 36,
      question: 'Consider the food chain: Grass → Grasshopper → Frog → Snake → Hawk. In this food chain,',
      options: [
        'more number of hawks than grasshoppers can be supported',
        'more number of grasshoppers than hawks can be supported',
        'equal number of hawks and grasshoppers can be supported',
        'none of these'
      ],
      answer: 'more number of grasshoppers than hawks can be supported'
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question: 'There is more biodiversity in areas with',
      options: [
        'less competition, less predation',
        'less competition, more predation',
        'more competition, more predation',
        'more competition, less predation'
      ],
      answer: 'more competition, more predation'
    }
  ]